# Ardra T Shaju

ardrashaju1997@gmail.com | M: +919061107565 | Thamarassery House, Kanippayyur (PO), Kunnankulam, Thrissur-680517, Kerala, India.

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Biochemist with **2 years** of biopharmaceutical industry research experience in the areas of **biochemical assays**, **cell biology** and **drug discovery** from natural sources. Able to generate reports and model data. Collaborative team player who can easily adopt and apply accurate research methodology, data analysis strategies to obtain accurate results. Seeking for scientist position in Biotech/Bio pharma industries.

#### **WORK HISTORY**

## Sami-Sabinsa Group Ltd. Bangalore, KA, India

Junior Scientist, Bioresearch R&D 12/2021 - 5/2023

- Doing *In-vitro* assays to study the mechanism of action of the drugs.
- Developing/standardizing new methods as per the company requirement.
- Managing documentation as per NABL guidelines and purchase orders

## Amala Cancer Research Centre. Thrissur, Kerala, India

Intern Trainee 10/2021- 12/2021

Project: 'Evaluation and comparison of blood antioxidant status in Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD) patients and healthy control'.

# Bioresearch- semi-automated medical Diagnostic Laboratory

Intern Trainee 08/2021 - 10/2021

- Recording incoming sample identity in the log books.
- Processing blood, urine sample for different clinical diagnosis parameters.
- Preparing test report

# <u>College of Veterinary and Animal Science</u>. Mannuthy, Thrissur, Kerala, India

M.Sc. project|

• Topic: Molecular Characterization of Partial Mitochondrial 16S rRNA Gene to Identify Meat from Avian Species.

· Works: DNA isolation from poultry meat, PCR, RFLP.

#### **SKILLS**

• Cell culture techniques:- Maintaining cancer cells, transformed cells and primary cells; Performing cell based assays. (Cytotoxicity; anti-inflammation; anti-oxidant and antiobesity;

photo toxicity; phagocytosis)

• Molecular biology: - DNA/RNA isolation, PCR.

• Biochemistry:- Optimization and validation of enzymatic and non-enzymatic assays

• Immunology:- ELISA

• Software skills:- Graphpad Prism, GelDoc XR+ documentation system

• Instruments handling:- Microplate reader(TECAN), Fluorescence microplate reader(Fluostar

optima), UV-VIS Spectrophotometer.

• Computer skills:- MS Word; Excel; Power point presentation

• Experienced in documentation as per NABL guidelines

## **EDUCATION**

# College of Veterinary and Animal Sciences

Mannuthy, Thrissur, Kerala, India.

2021

Master of Science: Biochemistry & Molecular Biology

Affiliated to Kerala Veterinary and Animal Sciences University Pookode, Wayanad, Kerala,

India

### Sree Krishna College

Ariyanoor, Thrissur, Kerala, India

2018

Bachelor of Science: Biochemistry

Affiliated to Calicut University, Calicut, Kerala, India.